Finding Aid for Robert King papers, 1887-1942
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert King papers 1887-1942
King, Robert
1 linear foot
851635 Aa 2
Mining company superintendent; correspondence, reports, background information, and financial miscellanea.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from Mrs. William G. Cloon (donor no. 3015 ) and William Cloon, Jr. (donor no. 5249 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Robert King was superintendent of the Ashland Iron Mining Company at Hurley, Wisconsin, and the Hayes Mining Company at Ironwood, Michigan.
The collection consists of business correspondence relating to mining activities. There is some correspondence with members of the Hayes family, including California Congressman, Everis A. Hayes, and newspaper publisher and fruit raiser, J.O. Hayes. In addition, the collection includes reports of mining developments and disasters in the 1880's and 1890's, documentation of the Germania Mine, information about Hurley Wisconsin, travel diaries, and miscellaneous ledgers.
Subjects:
Ashland Iron Mining Company.; Business records.; Gogebic County (Mich.); Hayes Mining Company.; Hurley (Wis.); Iron mines and mining--Wisconsin--Hurley.; Iron mines and mining--Michigan--Ironwood.; Ironwood (Mich.)
Contributors:
Hayes, E. A. (Everis Anson), 1855-1942.; Hayes, Jay Orley, 1857-1948.
Genre Terms:
Diaries
- Correspondence, 1887-1942
  - 1887-1890, 4 folders (Box 1)
    (arranged alphabetically)
  - 1900-1910 (Box 1)
  - 1911-1914 (Box 1)
  - 1915 (Box 1)
  - 1916-1917 (Box 1)
  - 1918 (Box 1)
  - 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920 (Box 1)
  - 1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922-1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924 (Box 1)
  - 1925 (Box 1)
  - 1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927 (Box 1)
  - 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - 1934-1942 (Box 1)
- Other papers, undated and 1880s-1929
  - Reports of Mining Developments and Disasters in the 1880s and 1890s (Box 1)
  - 1926-1929 (Hayes Mining Co.) (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning history of Hurley, Wisconsin (Box 1)
  - Germania Mine -- log of daily progress, 1899-1925 (Box 1)
  - Travel diary, 1909-1926 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Ledgers and journals (Box 1)